jstor.org 2019-12-23

# Privacy Policy | ITHAKA

This privacy statement describes how ITHAKA collects and uses the personal information you provide on our websites: [www.ithaka.org](http://www.ithaka.org/), [www.jstor.org](https://www.jstor.org/), [www.artstor.org](https://www.artstor.org/), [www.sr.ithaka.org](http://www.sr.ithaka.org/), and [www.portico.org](http://www.portico.org/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. ITHAKA is committed to protecting the privacy of users of its website and services, including users of JSTOR and JSTOR-branded services (Journals Hosting Program, Individual Access, Publisher Sales Service), Artstor services (Artstor Digital Library, JSTOR Forum, SAHARA, Copyright Checkpoint, and the Images for Academic Publishing (IAP) service ), Ithaka S+R, JSTOR Global Plants and Portico (collectively, “ITHAKA Websites”). To better inform you of our policy concerning user privacy, we have adopted the following terms, which adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles issued by the U.S. Department of Commerce.

The Information ITHAKA Collects

Data Integrity; Use of the Information

Use of Cookies

Other Tracking Technologies and Automated-Decision Making Practices

Widgets

Onward Transfer of Information

Your Consent; Opting Out

Security

Access, Erasure, and Correction

Data Retention

Testimonials

Enforcement and Dispute Resolution

Notification of Privacy Policy Changes

Contact Us

### The Information ITHAKA Collects

The personal information that ITHAKA collects will depend on how you are using ITHAKA Websites.

  * To enable your access to the JSTOR, Artstor, and Portico services through your library or institution, we may collect information concerning the institution’s internet protocol address, your username and password, or other authentication methods, such as Shibboleth.
  * To facilitate your order through the Publisher Sales Service (a service through the JSTOR archive that facilitates the purchase of articles from publishers), JPASS, the Journals Hosting Program, and Individual Access, as well as your purchase of ITHAKA and its services’ brand merchandise, we may collect your name, postal address, email address and transactional information. We collect but do not store your credit card details through a third party service provider.
  * In connection with your creation of a personal JSTOR account and/or a JSTOR Global Plants MyPLANTS (“MyPlants”) account, we collect your name, email address, username, and password, as well as other information you may provide.
  * In connection with your creation of an Artstor account, which is required to download images, save them to groups, create presentations and share them with other Artstor users, upload content to Personal Collections, and manage content in JSTOR Forum, we collect your email address, password, and institutional affiliation information; however, as a general user, you can perform searches of and view the Artstor Digital Library collections, IAP collections, your institution’s hosted collections in JSTOR Forum, and images made more broadly available through JSTOR Forum without providing any further information.
  * To enable you to download images from the IAP service for publication purposes we collect and share with the institution providing the images for publication your name, email address, institutional affiliation, and other information you may provide.
  * In connection with a trial access request for Artstor Digital Library or JSTOR Forum, we collect your name, email address, phone number, institutional affiliation information, and other information you may provide.
  * We also may collect certain non-personally identifiable information, such as the type of browser you are using (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows or Mac), and the domain name of your Internet service provider.

  * We may collect personal information through correspondence you send to us through optional surveys we may post on ITHAKA Websites, and in connection with statements you may post on any ITHAKA-related page on social networking sites.
  * In some instances, Ithaka S+R may be contracted to provide services to third parties, which may involve collecting your personal information. In such cases, the privacy policy governing the collection of your personal information shall be as set forth in such third parties’ privacy policies.
  * If you choose to use an available function on JSTOR to send a link, citation list, or other information to another person, we will ask you for that person’s email address for processing purposes only and will send that person one e-mail with the relevant information. ITHAKA will not store the recipient’s e-mail address once the one-time email has been sent. If you do not have a personal JSTOR account, we will also ask for your e-mail address and likewise only use it one time for processing purposes.

However, unless you provide us or organizations with which we conduct business with personal information, you remain anonymous to us other than by association with an internet protocol address or other authentication mechanism. Please note we do not store the text submitted via copyright assessment tool on the Copyright Checkpoint website.

In the case of Artstor services, some institutions facilitate their users’ use of their digital resources by providing administrative support for such resources, such as helping set up users’ accounts, or removing materials that are no longer needed. To provide such support, one or more representatives at an institution, such as a library administrator (“Institutional Administrator”), may need to associate electronic materials with the individual who created them, so that they can determine, for example, whether a particular user wants to continue to maintain such materials. If you elect to register as a user of an Artstor website, you give ITHAKA permission to provide the Institutional Administrator the email address that was used to register with Artstor. You also give the Institutional Administrator or ITHAKA (should the Institutional Administrator so direct us) permission to access the image groups or other materials that you have created, to make changes to such materials (including deleting such materials, either in full or in part), and to contact you at the email address provided with respect to such materials, for the purpose of administering and supporting the institution’s subscription to the Artstor services and websites. Your permission to the Institutional Administrator and ITHAKA to perform these roles does not necessarily imply that these activities will be performed at your particular institution. Please contact your Institutional Administrator if you have questions about institutional policy in this area.

ITHAKA does not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 16. If it is discovered that we have collected PII from someone under 16 we promptly will delete that information.

### Data Integrity; Use of the Information

We use the personal information collected in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was intended to be used: to enable your use of ITHAKA Websites and ITHAKA’s services; to facilitate JPASS and the Publisher Sales Service; to create your personal JSTOR and/or a MyPlants account; to facilitate your purchase of ITHAKA-branded merchandise; to respond to your inquiries; for system administration, customer support, and troubleshooting purposes; for new product announcements and product updates; for service announcements; for sending newsletters; to improve the design of ITHAKA Websites; to correspond with users; to enable us to enforce each of our JSTOR, Arstor, and Portico Terms and Conditions of Use; and in aggregate form, to track and analyze site usage. Further, in connection with postings you may make that are available to the general public on any ITHAKA-related page on social networking sites, including but not limited to statements made on the JSTOR or Artstor page on Facebook and on Twitter, we may use your name, statement, comment, and affiliation in conference presentations, ITHAKA’s (including JSTOR's, Artstor's, and Portico’s’) newsletters, and marketing and announcement materials. ITHAKA will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is relevant to its intended use, accurate, complete, and current. If you wish to opt out of our use of your personal information see the “Your Consent; Opting out” section below.

### Use of Cookies and Behavioral Targeting

ITHAKA employs “cookie” technology. Cookies are small pieces of text that are stored on your computer and act as a tool for controlling certain system variables and storing system configuration information in the WWW environment. ITHAKA uses cookies or similar technologies to store user preferences for viewing and printing, regional and geographical information connected to an IP address, and to store authentication information. We do not use cookies to identify what other sites you have visited; however, we do use certain tools to understand the flow of traffic to and from ITHAKA websites. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. Third party service providers may use cookies or similar technologies to make it easier for you to navigate our site or, if you use the provided social sharing widgets on our site, to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities, but those cookies are not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies, if used, but there are associations which may assist with opting-out of receiving personalized ads from third party advertisers (for more information please see <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/> or in the European Union <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>). For more information, please see our Cookie Policy at [https://www.ithaka.org/cookies.](https://www.ithaka.org/cookies)

### Other Tracking Technologies and Automated-Decision Making Practices

As with most web sites, ITHAKA gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

Through this policy, we will notify individuals of any automated-decision making practices we may engage in regarding PII, including the logic involved and the significance of the decision as well as the consequences for you. We also will ensure that you may opt out of such automated-decision making practices.

### Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets such as the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site (“Features”). These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Features to function properly. Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant Feature.

### Onward Transfer of Information

ITHAKA may work with other organizations that provide specific services for us, such as credit card processing. We will provide only the personal information necessary for the third party to provide these services for us. These organizations may not use personal information except for the purpose of providing these services.

ITHAKA may also transfer personal information to third parties, including third parties located internationally, such as applicable publishers, other content providers, and libraries, who can better assist with your inquiries, to facilitate order fulfillment for the Journals Hosting Program, and to enable them to inform users of services provided by ITHAKA and/or the third parties’ products and services that may be of interest. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate security measures. In addition, when transferring personally identifying information that is subject to the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR), we require a GDPR-approved transfer mechanism to be in place, such as Binding Corporate Rules or Privacy Shield Certification.

ITHAKA does not sell or share personal information about or the purchasing history of individual users, except as set forth above and in the following circumstances:

  * In certain situations, ITHAKA may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements;
  * If required to do so by law or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to comply with the law or a legal proceeding such as to comply to a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings or similar legal process; to protect against violations of our Terms and Conditions of Use; or to protect and defend our rights and property or the rights and property of rights holders whose content is made available through ITHAKA Websites;
  * With service providers with whom we have entered into agreements to assist us with our business operations;
  * If ITHAKA is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information;
  * If Ithaka S+R is contracted to provide services to third parties that involve collecting your personal information, the privacy policy governing the collection of your personal information shall be as set forth in such third parties’ privacy policies; and if you are accessing JSTOR through a token provided by your institution, on request from the institution solely for user verification purposes by the institution that provided the token; and other third parties, such as an institution with which you are affiliated, where you explicitly consent to our sharing your information.
  * With respect to IAP images, with the content providers who provided those images for publication, when a user downloads an image for use in a publication.

In addition, ITHAKA shares general usage data in aggregated form so that no personal information is identifiable to participating institutions, content providers, researchers, and the general public. ITHAKA will provide you all of your retained personal information provided at registration (where applicable) on request.

### Your Consent; Opting Out

By using ITHAKA Websites, you consent to the collection and use, in accordance with this policy, of the information you provide to us. We will remove you and your personal information from our records or refrain from using your personal information in connection with certain services on request if you contact us with your request at [privacy@ithaka.org](mailto:privacy@ithaka.org). Please note that this may prevent you from accessing ITHAKA’s services, including JSTOR, your personal JSTOR account, Publisher Sales Service, and certain Artstor websites and services.

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at [privacy@ithaka.org](mailto:privacy@ithaka.org).

### Security

We protect your personal information from unauthorized access and disclosure through the use of passwords, physical security measures, managerial measures, and (in connection with credit card information for order sales through JPASS, the Publisher Sales Service, Journals Hosting Program, Individual Access, and for purchase of ITHAKA and its services’ brand merchandise) encryption through our third party service providers. We nonetheless recognize that third parties may obtain access to information through unlawful actions, and thus do not promise that your information always will remain private, despite our efforts and the importance we place on maintaining your privacy. In addition, we do not claim any responsibility for information collected by or from websites linking to or from ITHAKA Websites.

In the event that we discover or are notified of a security breach where personal information is at risk, we will notify you electronically if we have your email address. If you do not wish to be notified via email in the event of a breach, please contact us at [privacy@ithaka.org](mailto:privacy@ithaka.org).

### Access, Erasure, and Correction

Upon request ITHAKA will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If you would like to review, delete or update your information, you may contact us using the contact information below. We will permit you to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. Please note, because of the way we maintain certain services, after you delete or amend your information, residual copies may take a period of time before they are deleted from our active servers and may remain in our backup systems.

You will need to provide sufficient identifying information, such as your name and email address and possible additional identifying information as a security precaution.

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@ithaka.org](mailto:privacy@ithaka.org). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our website in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@ithaka.org](mailto:privacy@ithaka.org).

### Enforcement and Dispute Resolution

We engage in periodic self-assessment to ensure compliance with our Privacy Policy. We verify that the policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented, and where applicable, in conformity with the GDPR. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns with us using the contact information below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this policy.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. In addition, European Union data subjects may seek an administrative or judicial remedy or to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the member state of his or her habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement if the data subject considers that the processing of personal data relating to him or her infringes the GDPR. Information on how to file such a complaint is available here <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>.

As a not-for-profit organization, we are not subject to the jurisdiction of the United States Federal Trade Commission, which oversees the implementation of the Privacy Shield Principles; however, we agree to adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles in recognition of their importance in ensuring the protection of user information.

### Notification of Privacy Policy Changes

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any change in how we use your personal information we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account). We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Contact Us

If you have any inquiries about this Privacy Policy or its implementation, you may contact us at [privacy@ithaka.org](mailto:privacy@ithaka.org).

Or by mail at

ITHAKA

℅ Olga Susuni

101 Greenwich Street, 18th Floor

New York, New York 10006

Last updated on November 20, 2019
